Syed Hasnain Bukhari

CONTACT

Life Sukhumvit 48, floor 24th. 122 Sukhumvit Rd, Phra Khanong 10110 Bangkok Khlong Toei TH



syedhasnainbukhari01@hotma



(+66) 630789575. (+92) 3017924305



https://www.linkedin.com/in/has bukhari-30494184



https://www.linkedin.com/ in/ hasnain-bukhari-30494184



https://github.com/ Hasnain-Bukhari

EDUCATION

BACHELOR COMPUTER SCIENCE

Digital Logic Design Assembly Language Data Structures **Design Patterns** Web Programming **Compiler Construction** Concurrent and Distributed Systems

SYED HASNAIN BUKHARI

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with 5+ years of rich professional experience of building and delivering highly scalable, enterprise grade software products. I hold a Bachelor's degree in Computer Sciences from the Punjab University College of Information Technology, Lahore, Pakistan

EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Agoda | Dec 2021 - Present

Leading several teams, working on solutions based upon distributed computing to make the e-commerce scene under the global travel space alive

- Working with teams to migrate long-running legacy systems to a newer and a better stack
- Keeping track of the learning abilities of my team so that they can progress in their respective careers and interests
- Having 1:1s to shape up the team culture and align them with essential matters at the

High Performance Computing **Database Design** FAST - NUCES 2006 - 2010 SKILLS Web Development HTML Javascript Software Architecture Design-patterns Distributed systems Scalability Maintainability Software Development Sustainability Portability Scalability Reasonability **Problem Solving** CompetitiveProgramming Abstract **Draft documentation** docsify Github MARP Joplin MermaidJS FormsIO Communication face-2-face emails presentations conference buy-in talks negotiations

layman conversions 1:1s

- organization
- Build a mindset and culture of quality first;
 Owning our stuff and converting them to quality artefacts and systems
- Help the organization envision what moving away from legacy could mean and preach the benefits within the team(s)
- Help the team understand Agility at work and take them through ceremonies; This helps the team give their best following sprints
- Making an effort around organizational values, so it lives within the team and work we do.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Strategic System International | Nov 2019 - Dec 2021 (2 years 1 month)

Design and developed multiple major modules and provide technical support to web application as well mobile application. My responsibilities include:

- Building micro services oriented systems that enable integration with various external systems.
- Working in an agile, scrum environment using .NET stack to design and build highly optimized solutions to be deployed at a global scale.
- Optimizing and refactoring existing modules to accommodate new functionality and enhance performance and maintainability.
- Design and develop timesheets management module based on types of systems. User can track workings hours and working experience with different clients. User can upload paper timesheets as well.
- Implementation of Elastic search to enhance the performance and visualize the data.
- Provide technical to mobile application
- Provide technical support and consultancy to other projects as well

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CureMD | Sep 2017 - Nov 2019 (2 years 2 months)

Developed multiple major projects, as a full stack .NET developer as well as a software architect. My responsibilities include:

 Building highly scalable and robust, serviceoriented systems that enable integration of our

- flagship product with various external information exchange partners.
- Working in an agile, scrum environment using .NET stack to design and build highly optimized solutions to be deployed at a global scale.
- Providing technical and client support to various deployed products. Co-ordinate and plan inter and intra team activities.
- Restructure and refactor modules of existing products to accommodate new functionality and enhance performance and maintainability.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Logix Infinity | Jun 2016 - Sep 2017 (1 year 3 months)

Worked as a software developer, specializing in web and desktop application development, mainly using the .NET stack along with other web technologies (Angular, Ionic and JavaScript). It gave me a chance to work on an array of diverse projects, offering me a great learning experience and exposure. I've developed web-based software using ASP.NET (MVC, WEB API, .NetCore), Angular/Ionic and SQLServer.

AWARDS

- IASA IT Architecture Core (ITAC) CITAF
 Certification | May 2015 | Iasa Global
 Anchors to the beginning of Architect position
 and responsibilities
- Won the GIKI SOFTCOM 08 (Programming Competition) | Apr 2008 | GIKI University Pakistan
 A speed programming competition of national level

LANGUAGES

- Urdu | Native speaker
- English | Fluent

INTERESTS

- Home improvements & engineering
 Plumbing Electric-appliances Civil engineering
- Software based home solutions

loT Home-server plex raspberry-pi cups

• Watching documentaries

Idiocracy Lord-of-the-rings movies documentaries

REFERENCES

Amir is surely missed by his team/peers and I think any company would find great benefit with the addition of Amir to their leadership and technical team. Wish you all the best Amir and hope our paths cross again.

— Heinrich Rust

As a colleague Amir is friendly, personable, has an easy manner and great sense of humour. A clear communicator with a voice for radio, Amir is wise head on young shoulders.

- Paul Fitzgerald